YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 3. National Administrative Office
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. FINANCE AND FINANCIAL DEVELOPMENT
  - Subseries A. Finance and Development
    - Committees
      - Corporation and Foundation Support, 1967-70 (Box 193, Folder 19)
      - Endowment, 1940-41 (Box 193, Folder 20)
      - Finance Commission, 1933 (Box 193, Folder 21)
      - Finance Committee, 1984-87 (Box 194, Folder 1)
      - Financial Growth Group, 1979-82 (Box 194, Folder 2-3)
      - Financing the National Board, 1947-48 (Box 194, Folder 4)
      - Local Association Financial Development, 1972-74 (Box 194, Folder 5)
      - Long Range Finance, 1964-72 (Box 194, Folder 6)
      - Long Range Financial Planning, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 7)
      - National Affiliation Dues Subcommittee, 1996-97 (Box 194, Folder 8-9)
      - National Support Task Force
        - General, 1991-93 (Box 194, Folder 10)
        - Mid-Triennial Meetings: notes, Apr-May 1993 (Box 194, Folder 11)
      - Special Gifts, 1964-67 (Box 194, Folder 12)
      - World Service Council
        - General information pamphlets, 1933-90, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 13)
        - History and organization
          - 1920-29 (Box 194, Folder 14-15)
          - 1930-94 (Box 195, Folder 1)
        - Meetings
          - 1920-32 (Box 195, Folder 2)
          - Annual Meetings
            - 1935-87 (Box 195, Folder 3-13)
            - 1988-2002 (Box 196, Folder 1-11)
          - Executive Committee
            - 1921-25, 1973-89 (Box 196, Folder 12-15)
            - 1990-2002 (Box 197, Folder 1-8)
          - with National staff, 1992-95 (Box 197, Folder 9)
          - Regional, 1926-36 (Box 197, Folder 10)
          - Convention, 1940-61, 1991-98 (Box 197, Folder 11-16)
          - Miscellaneous invitations, 1916-88, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 17)
        - Reports
          - General, 1920-87 (Box 198, Folder 1)
          - Anna Caldwell, Secretary to WSC, 1923-33 (Box 198, Folder 2)
          - Annual, 1989-2001 (Box 198, Folder 3-6)
        - Mailings
          - 1921-91 (Box 198, Folder 7-10)
          - 1992-2000 (Box 199, Folder 1)
        - Memos and correspondence, 1926-2000 (Box 199, Folder 2-7)
        - Membership
          - Directories, 1942-2001 (Box 199, Folder 8-9)
          - Rosters, 1921-69, n.d. (Box 199, Folder 10)
          - Changes, 1926-27, 1991-2000, n.d. (Box 199, Folder 11)
          - Correspondence, 1949-2000, n.d. (Box 199, Folder 12)
        - Finances
          - General, 1986-2000 (Box 199, Folder 13)
          - Contributions, 1923-50, 1987-99 (Box 200, Folder 1-2)
          - Archives project, 1997-2000 (Box 200, Folder 3)
          - International Building Fund, 1987-96, n.d. (Box 200, Folder 4)
          - Mary Rockefeller Memorial Fund, 1997 (Box 200, Folder 5)
          - World YWCA centenary celebration, 1994 (Box 200, Folder 6)
        - Serial publications
          - World Service Bulletin, 1921 (Box 200, Folder 7)
          - World Service Council News Sheet, 1928-37 (Box 200, Folder 8-11)
          - World Service Council News Letter, 1938-62 (Box 200, Folder 12-13)
          - World Service Council newsletter, 1994-2000 (Box 200, Folder 14)
    - Publications, [see also National Support Sample Books-oversize boxes]
      - Financial Development/publicity
        - Chronological file
          - 1920-29 (Box 200, Folder 15-18)
          - 1930-45 (Box 201, Folder 1-10)
          - 1946-85, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 1-14)
        - Christmas reminders, 1949-83 (Box 203, Folder 1)
        - Donor Report, 1997-99 (Box 203, Folder 2)
        - Serials
          - Close-Ups, 1929-38 (Box 203, Folder 3)
          - National YWCA Dollar/Dollar Highlights, 1935-86 (Box 203, Folder 4-5)
          - Travelog, 1936-41 (Box 203, Folder 6)
          - World Fellowship Bulletin, 1946-48 (Box 203, Folder 7)
          - YWCA News, 1936-71 (Box 203, Folder 8-9)
          - Financial Development Bulletin, 1991-92 (Box 203, Folder 10)
      - Forms and Guidelines
        - Finance Statement and National Support Payment forms, 1963-80 (Box 203, Folder 11-12)
        - National Support Kit
          - 1958-64, 1973-76, 1987-88 (Box 203, Folder 13-16)
          - 1989-91 (Box 204, Folder 1-3)
      - Manuals and handbooks
        - Budgeting
          - Personal and family, 1921, n.d. (Box 204, Folder 4)
          - "Suggested Budget Form for Young Women's Christian Associations," 1930-47 (Box 204, Folder 5)
          - Budget and Finance Manual for the YWCA, 1953 (Box 204, Folder 6)
        - Finance Administration Manual for the YWCA, 1966-80 (Box 204, Folder 7-10)
        - Finance, general, 1915-48 (Box 204, Folder 11-12)
        - The Finance Committee, 1936, 1940 (Box 205, Folder 1)
        - Fundraising
          - General, 1932, 1953-81, circa 1990 (Box 205, Folder 2-4)
          - Building campaigns, 1913-19 (Box 205, Folder 5)
          - Funds and Friends by Tolman Lee, 1925 (Box 205, Folder 6)
          - Major Gifts Campaign Solicitors Handbook, 1989, 1992 (Box 205, Folder 7-8)
          - Scrapbooks [disassembled]
            - 1919-33 (Box 205, Folder 9-10)
            - 1934-38 (Box 206, Folder 1)
        - Suggestions for an Accounting Plan for a Non-Profit Organization-The YWCA by Frederick J. Haller, 1936 (Box 206, Folder 2)
    - Reports
      - Department/Division, 1907-18, 1920-23, 1930-31 (Box 206, Folder 3-6)
      - Finance Committee, 1934-64 (Box 206, Folder 7-8)
      - Office Secretary, 1909-19 (Box 206, Folder 9)
      - Secretaries and special workers, Visitation Reports
        - Ella G. Agnew, 1920 (Box 206, Folder 10)
        - Esther Anderson, 1916-20 (Box 206, Folder 11)
        - Helen Ballard, 1913-15 (Box 206, Folder 12)
        - Helen Barnes, 1917-20 (Box 206, Folder 13)
        - Augusta Brown, 1909-12 (Box 206, Folder 14)
        - Mary Colt, 1919-20 (Box 206, Folder 15)
        - Katharine Condon, 1919-20 (Box 206, Folder 16)
        - Edith Helmer, 1918-19 (Box 206, Folder 17)
        - Elizabeth Hughes, 1918-20 (Box 206, Folder 18)
        - Mary Johns [Hopper], 1919 (Box 206, Folder 19)
        - Sada Johnson, 1918-19 (Box 206, Folder 20)
        - Edith Keeley, 1919-20 (Box 206, Folder 21)
        - Julia Lee, 1917-20 (Box 206, Folder 22)
        - Mary McElroy, 1917-1918 (Box 206, Folder 23)
        - Mary Childs Nerney, 1919-20 (Box 207, Folder 1)
        - Clara S. Roe, 1919 (Box 207, Folder 2)
        - Ella Schooley, 1916-1919 (Box 207, Folder 3)
        - Mabel K. Stafford, 1919-20 (Box 207, Folder 4)
        - Edith N. Stanton, 1913 (Box 207, Folder 5)
        - Cora Tatham, 1919-20 (Box 207, Folder 6)
        - Harriet Taylor, 1910-17 (Box 207, Folder 7)
        - Edith Wilkinson, 1910-19 (Box 207, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous, 1911-12, 1920 (Box 207, Folder 9)
      - Committee for National Support and Interpretation, 1933-78, 1992 (Box 207, Folder 10-17)
      - Committee on Financing the National Board, 1940-48 (Box 207, Folder 18)
    - Studies
      - "A Fund-Raising Study and Report on the Foreign Division…," John Price Jones Corporation, 1946 (Box 207, Folder 19)
      - "Study and Recommendations Concerning the Public Relations, Publicity and Fund-Raising of the National Board…," John Price Jones Corporation, 1947 (Box 207, Folder 20)
      - Appraisal of the National Support and Public Information Departments, John Price Jones Corporation, 1949 (Box 207, Folder 21)
      - "Findings and Recommendations for Increasing Financial Support of the National Board of the YWCA," Greenleigh Associates, Inc., 1963 (Box 207, Folder 22)
    - Training
      - Finance Workshop packet, Houston, Texas, Nov 1972 (Box 208, Folder 1)
      - Finance Management Workshop, YWCA Leadership Training Institute, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2)
      - Financial Development Workshops
        - General, 1973-96 (Box 208, Folder 3)
        - Institutes, 1986-87 (Box 208, Folder 4)
        - Kit and Presentation materials, 1987 (Box 208, Folder 5)
        - Columbus, Ohio, Apr 1987 (Box 208, Folder 6)
        - St. Louis, Missouri, Dec 1987 (Box 208, Folder 7)
        - New Orleans, Louisiana, Jan 1988 (Box 208, Folder 8)
        - San Diego, California, Mar 1988 (Box 208, Folder 9)
      - Financial Planning Workshop, Cluster Meetings, 1977 (Box 208, Folder 10)
      - Money Management Seminar, Jun 1978 (Box 208, Folder 11)
      - Planned Giving Workshops, 1986-88 (Box 208, Folder 12-14)
      - Proposal writing, 1965-74, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 15)
      - Resource Development Workshop, 1998 (Box 208, Folder 16)
    - Fundraising, General
      - General, 1945-96, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 17-18)
      - Annual Fund, 1996-99, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 19)
      - Communications and Knowledge Sharing Project, 1998 (Box 208, Folder 20)
      - Community Associations, 1913, 1963-97, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 21)
      - Corporate Partnership Policy, 1991-92 (Box 209, Folder 1)
      - Direct mail
        - Appeals, 1980-96, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2-3)
        - Consultation, 1980 (Box 209, Folder 4)
      - Executive Management for Women, 1975-76, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 5)
      - Grants
        - Foundations
          - General, 1979-98, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 6-8)
          - Fleischmann Foundation, 1975-79 (Box 209, Folder 9)
        - Government
          - General, 1963-6, 1973-92 (Box 209, Folder 10-11)
          - Research and Action, Inc.
            - General, 1971 (Box 209, Folder 12)
            - Technical Assistance Project, 1977-78 (Box 209, Folder 13)
            - Information Brief about Government Programs, 1974-83 (Box 209, Folder 14)
      - Mabel Cratty Endowment Fund, 1928-40 (Box 210, Folder 1)
      - National Support (aka Quotas, fee sharing, shared membership dues)
        - General, 1927-96, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2-8)
        - Form letters, 1988-92 (Box 210, Folder 9)
        - Plans, circa 1920-98 (Box 210, Folder 10-15)
        - Videotape, 1986-87 (Box 210, Folder 16)
      - National YWCA Associates
        - General, 1933-52 (Box 211, Folder 1)
        - Mailings, 1933-35 (Box 211, Folder 2)
      - Planned/deferred giving
        - General, 1954-94, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 3-4)
        - Grace Dodge Legacy Club, 1988-94 (Box 211, Folder 5)
        - Pooled Income Fund, 1976-93 (Box 211, Folder 6)
      - Tribute to Women in International Industry (TWIN), 1978-92, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 7-9)
      - Campaigns
        - Sunday Campaign, 1917 (Box 211, Folder 10)
        - Assurance Policy Campaign, 1922-23 (Box 211, Folder 11)
        - End of Year Endowment Appeal, 1951 (Box 211, Folder 12)
        - Centennial Fund
          - General, 1953-57, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 13-14)
          - Sample Corporation Appeal, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 15)
        - Fund for the Future, 1980-86
          - General, 1980-90, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 1)
          - Feasibility/Planning Study, Blakeley, John Price Jones Inc., 1980-81 (Box 212, Folder 2)
          - Case Statement, Jul 1982 (Box 212, Folder 3)
          - Meetings and reports, 1982-86 (Box 212, Folder 4)
          - Corporate appeals
            - Samples, 1983-88, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 5)
            - Proposal to Houston Industries Inc., 1986 (Box 212, Folder 6)
          - Donors, 1982-86, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 7)
          - Fund for the Future Bulletin, 1983-87 (Box 212, Folder 8)
          - Press kits, 1982, 1985 (Box 212, Folder 9)
          - Prospects, 1981-86, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 10-11)
        - Millennium 2000: Changing Lives, Building Futures, 1996-2000
          - General, 1996-98, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 12-13)
            - Case statement: drafts and text, 1995-98 (Box 212, Folder 14)
            - Case Advisory Committee meetings, 1997-98 (Box 213, Folder 1-2)
            - Mary French Rockefeller Distinguished Service Award plaques, 1998 (Box 213, Folder 3)
          - Campaign budget and plan, 1995-98, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 4)
          - Community Counseling Service Co., Inc.
            - Feasibility study, 1991 (Box 213, Folder 5)
            - Contracts, 1997-98 (Box 213, Folder 6)
            - Comprehensive Assessment of the Campaign, 1997 (Box 213, Folder 7)
          - Concept Papers
            - General, 1996-97, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 8)
            - Capacity Building, 1996-98 (Box 213, Folder 9)
            - ENCOREplus, 1997, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 10)
            - Racial Justice, 1996-97 (Box 213, Folder 11)
          - Events
            - Coffee and Cake hosted by Ruthanna Weber, 1998 (Box 213, Folder 12)
            - Tea hosted by Elisabeth Luce Moore, 1996 (Box 213, Folder 13)
            - Workshops, 1997, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 14)
          - 'Genesis Group': survey and consultation, 1998-99 (Box 213, Folder 15)
          - Gifts: policies and procedures, 1996-98, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 16)
          - Guide for Campaign Leaders, circa 1996 (Box 213, Folder 17)
          - Leadership
            - General, 1996-98, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 1-2)
            - Rosters, 1996-97 (Box 214, Folder 3)
            - Chairs/Co-Chairs, 1995-97, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 4)
            - Campaign Cabinet, 1995-98, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 5)
            - National Board involvement, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 6)
          - Meetings
            - Miscellaneous, 1995-98 (Box 214, Folder 7)
            - Campaign Executive Committee
              - Jan-Feb, 1998 (Box 214, Folder 8-9)
              - May 1998 (Box 214, Folder 10)
            - Campaign Cabinet, 1996-97 (Box 214, Folder 11)
            - Campaign staff, 1996-98 (Box 214, Folder 12-13)
            - Core Management Committee, 1997 (Box 215, Folder 1)
          - National-Regional partnership
            - General, 1998-99, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2-3)
            - Meetings, 1998 (Box 215, Folder 4-7)
          - Prospects
            - General, 1996-98 (Box 215, Folder 8-9)
            - Corporations and Foundations development plan and master lists, 1998 (Box 215, Folder 10)
            - Corporations
              - General, 1996-97, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 11)
              - Crains' List of Top 100 Minority Executives, 1998 (Box 215, Folder 12)
              - Citibank, 1998 (Box 215, Folder 13)
              - GTE Corporation, 1996-98 (Box 215, Folder 14)
              - Time Warner, Inc., 1998 (Box 216, Folder 1)
              - TRW, 1998 (Box 216, Folder 2)
              - USInternetworking, Inc., 1998 (Box 216, Folder 3)
              - USX Corporation, 1998 (Box 216, Folder 4)
            - Foundations
              - General, 1996-98, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 5-6)
              - Best Buy Children's Foundation, 1997-98 (Box 216, Folder 7)
              - Charles Stewart Mott Foundation, 1997 (Box 216, Folder 8)
              - Ford Foundation, 1995-96 (Box 216, Folder 9)
              - General Motors Foundation, 1998 (Box 216, Folder 10)
              - Starr Foundation, 1980-97 (Box 216, Folder 11)
              - Weyerhauser Family Foundation, 1997 (Box 216, Folder 12)
              - WK Kellogg Foundation, 1997 (Box 216, Folder 13)
            - Individuals
              - General, 1996-98, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 14-15)
              - Dayton, Mary Lee, 1995, 1998 (Box 216, Folder 16)
              - Gambrell, Sarah Belk, 1997-98 (Box 216, Folder 17)
              - Moore, Elisabeth Luce, 1995-98 (Box 216, Folder 18)
            - By program/initiative
              - General, 1996-97, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 19)
              - ENCOREplus, 1996-97, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 20)
              - Teen Pregnancy Prevention, 1997, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 1)
          - Reports
            - General, 1996-98 (Box 217, Folder 2-3)
            - 'Key Solicitations,' 1996-97 (Box 217, Folder 4)
      - Donors
        - Pauline Dodge, 1948-71 (Box 218, Folder 1)
        - Molly Dowell, 1970-78 (Box 218, Folder 2)
        - Eunice Draper, 1960-70 (Box 218, Folder 3)
        - Margaret W. Driscoll, 1967-82 (Box 218, Folder 4)
        - Marjorie C. Dudley, 1945-72 (Box 218, Folder 5)
        - Obie Dunklee, 1961-77 (Box 218, Folder 6)
        - Jane Du Pont, 1961-85 (Box 218, Folder 7)
        - Susan Eagan, 1943-1970 (Box 218, Folder 8)
        - Margaret Estey, 1979 (Box 218, Folder 9)
        - Eileen Farrell, 1976-85 (Box 218, Folder 10)
        - Margaret Gardiner, 1969-85 (Box 218, Folder 11)
        - Muriel Van Anden Gross, 1969-86 (Box 218, Folder 12)
        - Mr. Nicholas, 1975 (Box 218, Folder 13)
        - Margaret Oest, 1968-73 (Box 218, Folder 14)
        - Grace Gil Olivarez, 1971-72 (Box 218, Folder 15)
        - Mary O'Nan, 1969-75 (Box 218, Folder 16)
        - Virginia Outcalt, 1964-70 (Box 218, Folder 17)
        - Jean Owens, 1968-73 (Box 218, Folder 18)
        - Theresa Paist, 1968-76 (Box 218, Folder 19)
        - Emma Penn, 1968-73 (Box 218, Folder 20)
        - Jean Perkins, 1964-70 (Box 218, Folder 21)
        - Kathreen Pettit, 1966-72 (Box 218, Folder 22)
        - Eleanor Phipps, 1962-71 (Box 218, Folder 23)
        - Katherine B. Philips, 1973-75 (Box 218, Folder 24)
        - Patsy Lee King Phillips, 1973-75 (Box 218, Folder 25)
        - Isabel Pierce, 1962-82 (Box 218, Folder 26)
        - Helen B. Pryor, 1963-72 (Box 218, Folder 27)
        - Elizabeth Ramser, 1963-65 (Box 218, Folder 28)
        - Dr. Katharine Rea, 1968-70 (Box 218, Folder 29)
        - Laura Rea, 1977-79 (Box 218, Folder 30)
        - Clara Stillman Reed, 1970-76 (Box 218, Folder 31)
        - Betty Richards, 1974-75 (Box 218, Folder 32)
        - Lillian Rochester, 1949-72 (Box 218, Folder 33)
        - Mrs. William W. Rockwell, 1969-71 (Box 218, Folder 34)
        - Bernice Roe, 1963-84 (Box 218, Folder 35)
        - May Rogers, 1969-80 (Box 218, Folder 36)
        - Dorothy (Mrs. William Lister) Rogers, 1966-77 (Box 218, Folder 37)
        - Lenore Romney, 1966-77 (Box 218, Folder 38)
        - Marie Sander, 1962-83 (Box 218, Folder 39)
        - Luella (Mrs. Thomas) Sayman, 1963-77 (Box 218, Folder 40)
        - Mary Sandlin, 1965-83 (Box 219, Folder 1)
        - Sabra Sanders, 1966-74 (Box 219, Folder 2)
        - Esther Saunders, 1949-85 (Box 219, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Sayre, 1947-85 (Box 219, Folder 4-5)
        - Elizabeth Schemm, 1955-75 (Box 219, Folder 6)
        - Della Brooks Sels, 1967-74 (Box 219, Folder 7)
        - Jill Sheffield, 1970-78 (Box 219, Folder 8)
        - Georgiana Sibley, 1939-1980 (Box 219, Folder 9)
  - OVERSIZE
    - National Support Sample Books
      - 1939-45 (Box 220)
      - 1946-53 (Box 221)
      - 1954-62 (Box 222)
      - 1963-67 (Box 223)
  - Subseries B. Comptroller's Office
    - Budget
      - General, 1907-21, 1932-75, 1991-92 (Box 224, Folder 1-17)
      - Process, 1931-96 (Box 224, Folder 18)
      - Committees
        - Budget Reviewing Committee, 1930-34 (Box 224, Folder 19)
        - Committee on Review of Budget and Program, 1942 (Box 224, Folder 20)
        - Budget Apportionment Committee, 1944-47 (Box 224, Folder 21)
    - Financial Statements
      - 1907-38, 1969-83 (Box 224, Folder 22-23)
      - 1986-2002 (Box 225, Folder 1-2)
    - Reports
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-20, 1974-78 (Box 225, Folder 3)
      - Comptroller, 1933-54 (Box 225, Folder 4)
      - Finance Committee, 1936-45 (Box 225, Folder 5)
      - Treasurer, 1907-13, 1918, 1929-41, 1947-65 (Box 225, Folder 6-15)
    - Comptroller's Office/Financial Resources Department
      - General, 1965-90 (Box 226, Folder 1)
      - Accounting
        - Report of System of Accounts Installed at Headquarters, 1926 (Box 226, Folder 2)
        - Chart of Accounts, 1995-97 (Box 226, Folder 3)
      - Funds
        - General, 1923-97, n.d. (Box 226, Folder 4)
        - Capital Funds, 1947-56 (Box 226, Folder 5)
        - "Phoenix Account" for Troubled YWCAs, 1998 (Box 226, Folder 6)
        - Endowment
          - "Notes on Board Endowment," Finance Committee, 1940 (Box 226, Folder 7)
          - Endowed funds and restructuring of the national organization, 2002 (Box 226, Folder 8)
          - Asiatic Fund, 1996 (Box 226, Folder 9)
          - Dow International Scholarship Fund, 1922-66 (Box 226, Folder 10)
          - Katharine Parker Music Foundation, 1930-78 (Box 226, Folder 11)
      - Personnel-National Staff
        - Unemployment Insurance Plan, 1938 (Box 226, Folder 12)
        - Voluntary Early Retirement Incentive, 1992 (Box 226, Folder 13)
      - Programs and Projects
        - Canal Zone Service Unit: Auditor's reports, 1924-33 (Box 226, Folder 14)
        - Job Corps
          - General, 1964-65, n.d. (Box 226, Folder 15)
          - Women's Training Center, Pittsburgh, 1964 (Box 226, Folder 16)
          - Residential Training Center, 1967 (Box 226, Folder 17)
        - National Training School: ledger, 1923-34 (Box 226, Folder 18)
        - Scholarship loans, 1957-76 (Box 226, Folder 19)
        - Summer Youth Demonstration Project, 1967 (Box 226, Folder 20)
      - Real Estate
        - Properties notebook, 1917-53 (Box 227, Folder 1-14)
        - Asilomar
          - Deeds, 1913-53 (Box 227, Folder 15)
          - Easement, 1951 (Box 227, Folder 16)
          - Financial reports, 1914-20 (Box 227, Folder 17)
          - Inventories, 1941-42 (Box 227, Folder 18)
          - Agreements and contracts, 1927-31 (Box 227, Folder 19)
          - Leases and sale, 1942-51 (Box 227, Folder 20)
          - Correspondence, Mrs. Bartlett Heard, 1944-56 (Box 227, Folder 21)
        - Grace Dodge Hotel
          - General, 1937-41 (Box 227, Folder 22)
          - Sale, 1945 (Box 227, Folder 23)
        - National Board headquarters, 600 Lexington Ave.: appraisal and inventory, 1920 (Box 227, Folder 24)
        - Foreign property
          - China
            - General, 1919-41 (Box 228, Folder 1)
            - Correspondence, 1915-43 (Box 228, Folder 2)
            - Declaration of Trust, 1918-35 (Box 228, Folder 3)
            - Title, 1940-44 (Box 228, Folder 4)
            - Canton, 1929-40 (Box 228, Folder 5)
            - Foochow, 1915-40 (Box 228, Folder 6)
            - Hangchow, 1921-29 (Box 228, Folder 7)
            - Mukden, 1921-34 (Box 228, Folder 8)
            - Peiping, 1920-40 (Box 228, Folder 9)
          - Japan, 1926-38 (Box 228, Folder 10)
      - War Work Council, 1917-22 (Box 229, Folder 1)
      - Womans Press, sale of, 1952-53 (Box 229, Folder 2-4)
  - Subseries C. Miscellaneous
    - Emissarius Credit Union: minutes and reports, 1924-61 (Box 230, Folder 1-7)
    - YWCA Retirement Fund, Inc.
      - General and History, circa 1921-2002, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 1-3)
      - Annual Reports, 1955-97 (Box 231, Folder 4-6)
      - Directory, 1993, 1999 (Box 231, Folder 7-8)
      - YWCA Retirement Fund Task Force, 1992-93 (Box 231, Folder 9-10)
      - Newsletter, YWCA Retirement Fund, 1990-98 (Box 231, Folder 11)
    - YWCA Savings and Security Plan for Non-Secretarial Employees: general and reports, 1940-59 (Box 231, Folder 12)
- SERIES IV. DATA AND STATISTICS
  - General and History
    - General, 1941-90 (Box 232, Folder 1)
    - Statistics, miscellaneous, circa 1941-94, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2-3)
  - Committees
    - Interpretation of Data and Trends/Data and Trends Committee, 1940-43, 1949-50 (Box 232, Folder 4-5)
    - Program Study Committee, 1950-51 (Box 232, Folder 6)
    - Studies Committee/Research Committee, 1956-59 (Box 232, Folder 7)
    - Information Resource Management Committee, 1986 (Box 232, Folder 8)
  - Department
    - Laboratory Division, Records and Reports Department (precursor staff to Data and Trends), 1938-40 (Box 232, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1943-83 (Box 232, Folder 10-12)
      - "Outside" requests for information, 1954-67 (Box 232, Folder 13)
      - Community Chests and Councils of America, Social Statistics Project, 1946-49 (Box 232, Folder 14)
      - World YWCA survey of part-time employment, 1958 (Box 232, Folder 15)
    - Human Resources File, 1972 (Box 232, Folder 16)